<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ian-a-beard.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ian-a-beard.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-09T18:25:32+00:00</updated><id>https://ian-a-beard.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Colorado 14ers</title><link href="https://ian-a-beard.github.io/blog/2015/colorado14ers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Colorado 14ers"/><published>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ian-a-beard.github.io/blog/2015/colorado14ers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ian-a-beard.github.io/blog/2015/colorado14ers/"><![CDATA[<p>A 14er (pronounced fourteener) is a mountain whose summit is at least 14 thousand feet above sea level. In the state of Colorado, there are 58 “14ers,” and up until two weeks ago I had hiked 0 of them. One of the most famous peaks in Colorado Springs, Pikes Peak, is a 14er too, and several members of my family have hiked it. When back home in Ohio, my Aunt Becky and I would enthusiastically discuss our plans to take on the challenge and eventually hike some 14ers ourselves. Indeed, hiking a 14er is more tiresome then lower altitude summits because it can easily cause altitude sickness. This was the perfect kind of challenge for me to take on now that I had finished college. Thus, when it came time to decide what to do for my 21st birthday, I knew I had to finally hike a 14er.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/14ers-2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/14ers-2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/14ers-2-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/14ers-2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="quandary-peak">Quandary Peak</h3> <p>On the morning of my birthday at a grizzly 4:30 AM I, as well as my parents, cousin, uncle, and my uncle’s dog Tora, woke up and got ready with haste to head for the mountain in my uncle’s truck. Towards the end of our half hour drive to the trailhead, there was a big commotion when a deer crossed the street and collided with the front of the truck. The deer was no longer, and my dad and uncle got out to drag it off the road while my mom and cousin inspected the truck for damage. Nonetheless, we piled back into the truck for the remaining few minutes of our drive.</p> <p>After parking and double checking our gear, we started on foot towards the trail around 5:30 am (fact check). Once we got from the service road to the trail, it began with steep switchbacks through the woods. It took only a few minutes until everyone was audibly aspirating. Although just minutes ago I was feeling the morning chill, I already started shedding layers.</p> <p>My cousin, Raychel, kept discussing our eminent departure from the “tree line,” which I learned is the part of the mountain where there is enough oxygen for trees to grow. Once out of the tree line, the arboreal veil would be lifed revealing great vistas of nearby peakes. Above the tree line, the terrain became more rocky, too.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/14ers-3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/14ers-3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/14ers-3-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/14ers-3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Eventually, the trail leveled out before the final ascent to the summit. The “pitch” to the summit still had quite a bit of snow on it. We were wise to bring attachable spikes for our hiking boots which make it easier to hike throgh the snow.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/14ers-4-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/14ers-4-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/14ers-4-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/14ers-4.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/14ers-5-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/14ers-5-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/14ers-5-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/14ers-5.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="hiking"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recount my experiences hiking three mountains in Colorado]]></summary></entry></feed>